[Music]
there is one food that has more
polyphenol oxidase activity than a
banana and it's a vegetable that's not a
potato what vegetable turns brown that's
not a white potato a white mushroom
white button mushrooms are packed with
that polyphenol munching enzyme even
more so than bananas now for those of
you thinking don't worry don't expect to
be putting mushrooms in my smoothies
anytime soon some people add avocado to
smoothies or or make a chocolate avocado
pudding here's a question what if you
eat mushrooms with a meal packed with
polyphenol rich foods might they mix in
your stomach and decrease the absorption
of the anth thein and red cabbage or the
berries and dessert for instance you
could also imagine having some potatoes
or eggplant in a meal but note this is
for fresh produce the enzyme is
destroyed by cooking and remember we
should be cooking our white mushrooms
anyway because of the agaritine right so
problem solved who wants to cook their
bananas though what else can we put in a
smoothie uh my favorite is mango which
you can buy Frozen when it's not in
season do we have to worry about it
having polyphenol eating enzymes well
what happens when you cut open a mango
does it go Brown no so it's probably
fine and indeed when researchers
measured polyphenol oxidase activity and
a bunch of fruits and vegetables mango
had 500 times less than banana the Apple
doesn't surprise me since it goes Brown
so fast but what's with the Beet grains
uh better to use something like kale for
your green smoothies instead where
enzyme activity is
undetectable this study raises so many
interesting questions U should you not
add bananas to your oatmeal I no longer
add it to my cran chocolate pomegranate
breakfast bowl since I don't want to
lose any of the polyphenols but what if
you're not making something chocolatey
the study only tested the effects of the
enzyme on Cocoa flavonols like they
didn't check to see if mixing bananas
with berries would affect the berry
phytonutrients but the presumption is
that it would and what does this mean
for bottled smoothie drinks that you buy
off the shelf in the store well if
they've been pasteurized then it should
be okay since the heat should destroy
the enzyme that's why vegetables are
blanched before they're frozen to
destroy the enzymes even just heating
banana to 70° C which is like the
temperature of hot tea for 2 minutes and
the presence of vitamin C and citric
acid which might come from lemon juice
would suppress the enzyme by
80% I'm not suggesting drinking hot
smoothies but rather that depending on
the ingredients pasteurized smoothie
drinks may not share the same problem as
fresh-made smoothies
what about just the vitamin C and citric
acid alone like putting lemon juice in
your smoothie only cuts the enzyme
activity down by
133% works wonders on a cut Apple though
slashing enzyme activity nearly in half
which explains why lemon juice can keep
your fruit salad from turning brown
anything we can add to a banana smoothie
to inhibit the enzyme sulfites used to
be put on fresh fruits and vegetables
until they were banned in 1986 following
cases of sulfi induced asthma they're
still used in dried fruit though to
prevent Browning what about natural
agents onion extracts can prevent the
Browning of pears both fresh and cooked
onion juice but there's got to be a
better option for your smoothie
pineapple seems to help keep apples from
browning and bananas too but that was
after soaking in pineapple juice for 3
days so it's not clear if it would work
right away there was a study comparing
lemon juice and white wine to prevent
Brownie and pastry dough you've heard of
hard cider hard Seltzer the lemon juice
beat out the wine though so better a
Lemon Squeeze than drinking a hard
smoothie
[Music]